Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Kathryn and today we have an elementary level lesson for you all about computers.
我是Kathryn，今天我们为大家带来一节关于电脑的基础课程。
That's right.
没错。
So we are going to take a look at some of the basic parts of a computer and also about
所以我们要看看电脑的一些基本部件，还有关于
bad programs that could affect your computer and make it not work.
可能影响电脑并导致它无法正常工作的坏程序。
That's right.
没错。
So to get going, we have a verb for you that we're going to look at in vocabulary preview.
那么开始之前，我们有一个动词，会在词汇预览中介绍。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So today on vocabulary preview, we have a verb as you said, and it's to crash.
今天在词汇预览中，我们有一个动词，就像你说的，是“crash”。
To crash.
“Crash”。
Okay.
好的。
This has a couple of different meanings, but in today's dialogue, this means for your computer
这个词有几个不同的意思，但在今天的对话中，它指的是你的电脑
to shut down or to freeze or to stop working.
关机、死机或停止工作。
Right.
对。
So maybe you heard of a car crash, right?
你可能听说过“car crash”（车祸），对吧？
When two cars, bam, hit each other.
就是两辆车“砰”地撞在一起。
In this case, your computer is just not working anymore.
在这里，你的电脑就是不再工作了。
It stopped working.
它停止工作了。
It freezes.
它死机了。
That's right.
没错。
So you can't use it.
所以你就没法用了。
So my computer crashed is a way to say my computer stopped working.
所以“my computer crashed”就是说我的电脑停止工作了。
Okay.
好的。
So that's a word that we're going to listen in our dialogue today.
这就是我们今天对话中会听到的一个词。
Why don't we jump right into it and we'll be back shortly.
我们直接进入对话吧，稍后再回来。
Hello.
你好。
Thanks for calling one, two, three tech help.
感谢拨打123技术支持热线。
I'm Todd.
我是Todd。
How can I help you?
有什么可以帮您的？
Hello.
你好。
Can you help me on my computer?
你能帮我看看我的电脑吗？
Oh man.
哦，天哪。
It's okay, sir.
没事的，先生。
Calm down.
冷静点。
What happened?
发生什么事了？
I turned on my laptop and it broke.
我打开笔记本电脑，它就坏了。
I mean, the monitor went black.
我是说，显示器变黑了。
Okay, sir.
好的，先生。
It sounds like you might have a virus.
听起来你可能中了病毒。
I don't feel sick.
我没觉得不舒服啊。
Let me check.
让我检查一下。
Nope.
没有。
No fever.
没发烧。
I'm fine.
我很好。
No, your computer might have a virus.
不，是你的电脑可能中了病毒。
I mean, it has a bad program on it.
我是说，它上面有个坏程序。
Maybe that's why it crashed.
也许这就是它崩溃的原因。
I recommend that you run an antivirus program in order to safely remove any unwanted spyware
我建议你运行一个杀毒程序，以便安全地移除任何不需要的间谍软件
or trojans.
或木马。
Phew.
呼。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
Crash, spyware, trojans.
崩溃、间谍软件、木马。
What?
什么？
Where?
在哪？
When?
什么时候？
All right.
好的。
So lots of great technology words today.
今天有很多很棒的技术词汇。
Let's take a look at a few of them in Language Takeaway.
我们来看看“语言要点”中的几个。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
So let's start off with our first word.
我们先从第一个词开始。
You've probably heard it before, but let's go over it just in case.
你可能以前听过，但为了以防万一，我们还是过一遍。
A laptop.
“Laptop”（笔记本电脑）。
Laptop.
“Laptop”。
A laptop is a kind of computer.
笔记本电脑是一种电脑。
We have desktop, laptop.
我们有台式机和笔记本电脑。
Right.
对。
So your lap is the top part of your legs.
你的“lap”就是大腿的上部。
So a laptop computer is a small portable computer that you can take with you anywhere.
所以笔记本电脑是一种小巧便携的电脑，你可以随身携带。
That's right.
没错。
A lot of students have laptops and businessmen as well.
很多学生和商务人士都有笔记本电脑。
So you mentioned the opposite would be a desktop.
你提到了它的反义词是“desktop”（台式机）。
Right.
对。
So it sits on top of a desk.
所以它放在桌子上。
Okay.
好的。
So both a desktop and a laptop have monitors, a computer monitor.
台式机和笔记本电脑都有显示器，也就是电脑显示器。
So a monitor is like a TV for your computer.
显示器就像电脑的电视。
It's where you can see what you're doing.
你可以在上面看到你在做什么。
Okay.
好的。
So let's call it a monitor or a screen maybe.
那我们叫它显示器或者屏幕吧。
You can also use the word screen, but monitor is the technical word for the, usually a box,
你也可以用“屏幕”这个词，但“显示器”是技术术语，通常指一个盒子，
like a TV that goes with the desktop computer.
就像和台式电脑配套的电视一样。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So Todd, the computer guy said, Hey, I think your computer might have a virus.
所以，电脑专家托德说：“嘿，我觉得你的电脑可能中病毒了。”
Ooh, that doesn't sound good.
哦，听起来不妙。
Yeah.
是啊。
A virus.
病毒。
So I guess you know what a virus is when you get sick, right?
我想你知道生病时“病毒”是什么意思，对吧？
You get the flu or the cold.
你会得流感或感冒。
That's right.
没错。
You can say I have a virus, but how can a computer have a virus?
你可以说“我感染了病毒”，但电脑怎么会中病毒呢？
This means it's a program that is designed to hurt your computer.
这意味着它是一个旨在伤害你电脑的程序。
All right.
好的。
So it's like your computer is sick and it doesn't work.
所以就像你的电脑生病了，无法正常工作。
So a virus might make your computer crash.
所以病毒可能导致你的电脑崩溃。
Exactly.
没错。
So in order to avoid this, what we need is an antivirus program.
所以为了避免这种情况，我们需要一个杀毒程序。
Okay.
好的。
So virus is a bad thing.
所以病毒是坏东西。
Antivirus is a good thing.
杀毒是好事。
An antivirus program is a program that protects your computer from viruses.
杀毒程序是一个保护你电脑免受病毒侵害的程序。
So you would say antivirus.
所以你会说“杀毒”。
You might've heard of a very famous program called Norton antivirus or McAfee antivirus.
你可能听说过一个很有名的程序叫诺顿杀毒或迈克菲杀毒。
These are brands.
这些都是品牌。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So those are some of the main technical terms that we have on Language Takeaway.
这些就是我们在“语言要点”部分学到的一些主要技术术语。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue quickly once again.
我们快速再听一遍对话吧。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue quickly again and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
我们快速再听一遍对话，然后回来进行“流利度训练”。
Hello.
你好。
Thanks for calling 123 Tech Help.
感谢致电123技术帮助。
I'm Todd.
我是托德。
How can I help you?
有什么可以帮您？
Hello.
你好。
Can you help me?
你能帮我吗？
My computer.
我的电脑。
Oh man.
哦，天哪。
It's okay, sir.
没事的，先生。
Calm down.
冷静点。
What happened?
发生什么事了？
I turned on my laptop and it broke.
我打开笔记本电脑，它就坏了。
I mean, the monitor went black.
我是说，显示器变黑了。
Okay, sir.
好的，先生。
It sounds like you might have a virus.
听起来你可能中病毒了。
I don't feel sick.
我没觉得不舒服啊。
Let me check.
让我检查一下。
Nope.
没有。
No fever.
没发烧。
I'm fine.
我很好。
No, your computer might have a virus.
不，是你的电脑可能中病毒了。
I mean, it has a bad program on it.
我是说，它里面有个坏程序。
Maybe that's why it crashed.
也许这就是它崩溃的原因。
I recommend that you run an antivirus program in order to safely remove any unwanted spyware
我建议你运行一个杀毒程序，以便安全地移除任何不需要的间谍软件
or Trojans.
或木马。
Phew.
呼。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
Crash.
崩溃。
Spyware.
间谍软件。
Trojans.
木马。
What?
什么？
Where?
哪里？
When?
什么时候？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I'm just kidding.
我只是开玩笑。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now, let's start off with three key phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在，我们从“流利度训练”的三个关键短语开始。
This first phrase is one that I know you use a lot.
第一个短语我知道你经常用。
I use it too.
我也用。
We say, oh man.
我们说“哦，天哪”。
Oh man.
哦，天哪。
So now, depending on the tone, it can mean different things, right?
所以，根据语气不同，它可以表示不同的意思，对吧？
So in this case, what does it mean?
那么在这个例子中，它是什么意思？
So the man who's having problems with his computer says, my computer.
那个电脑出问题的男人说：“我的电脑。”
Oh man.
哦，天哪。
Right.
对。
He seems a little bit anguished.
他看起来有点痛苦。
Disappointed.
失望。
Yeah.
是的。
Oh man.
哦，天哪。
So, it's an interjection.
所以，这是一个感叹词。
That's right.
没错。
So you can say, oh man, my computer crashed.
所以你可以说，哦，天哪，我的电脑死机了。
Right.
对。
Oh man, you're always late.
哦，天哪，你总是迟到。
Now you can also say it for maybe surprise.
你也可以用它来表示惊讶。
Like oh man.
比如，哦，天哪。
So when you're excited about something, oh man, this computer game is awesome.
所以当你对某事感到兴奋时，哦，天哪，这个电脑游戏太棒了。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Okay.
好的。
So it's just a way of expressing maybe disappointment or in some cases, excitement.
所以它只是一种表达失望或某些情况下兴奋的方式。
Right.
对。
So think about the way that you say it.
所以想想你说话的方式。
Oh man.
哦，天哪。
Okay.
好的。
So now, the guy, Todd, he tells him, hey sir, it's okay.
所以现在，那个家伙，托德，他对他说，嘿，先生，没事的。
Calm down.
冷静点。
Right?
对吧？
Okay.
好的。
So this might be funny sounding because we say calm.
所以这听起来可能有点好笑，因为我们说“冷静”。
So be calm.
所以要冷静。
Calm down.
冷静下来。
This is a phrase.
这是一个短语。
It's almost like you're so upset and you're standing up.
就好像你非常沮丧，然后站了起来。
Calm down.
冷静下来。
Cool it.
别激动。
Okay.
好的。
So you tell someone to calm down.
所以你告诉某人冷静下来。
That's right.
没错。
So you might hear a parent say about their child, the child won't calm down.
所以你可能会听到父母说他们的孩子，孩子不肯冷静下来。
What do I do?
我该怎么办？
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Okay.
好的。
So it's a phrase.
所以这是一个短语。
Let's use it together.
我们一起用它。
Calm down.
冷静下来。
To calm down.
All right.
好的。
And now for our third phrase.
现在来看我们的第三个短语。
I mean.
我的意思是。
Okay.
好的。
So this is also an interjection and it's very, very, very common.
所以这也是一个感叹词，而且非常非常常见。
Okay.
好的。
So you'll probably hear people when they're talking, they're like, oh, I went over there.
所以你可能会听到人们在说话时，他们会说，哦，我去了那里。
I mean, we went to this place.
我的意思是，我们去了这个地方。
It's an interjection.
这是一个感叹词。
That's right.
没错。
And usually we say this when we want to correct what we just said.
通常当我们想纠正刚才说的话时，我们会这么说。
For example, your computer might have a virus.
例如，你的电脑可能中了病毒。
I mean, it has a bad program on it.
我的意思是，它上面有一个坏程序。
Okay.
好的。
So the computer support man, Todd, he understands maybe this person doesn't know what a virus
所以电脑支持人员托德，他明白这个人可能不知道什么是病毒。
is.
是什么。
So I mean, he's, he's changing what he just said.
所以我的意思是，他正在改变他刚才说的话。
We could say, oh, Saturday, I'm going to the movies.
我们可以说，哦，周六我要去看电影。
I mean, Sunday, I'm going to the movies.
我的意思是，周日我要去看电影。
Okay.
好的。
What are you doing on Sunday?
你周日要做什么？
Okay.
好的。
All right.
So you use it to correct yourself or maybe further explain something because maybe you
所以你用它来纠正自己，或者进一步解释某事，因为也许你在谈论一个话题，而对方可能不理解你，所以你想让它更清楚。
are talking about a topic and maybe the person is not understanding you so you want to make
更清楚。
it more clear.
没错。
That's right.
我的意思是。
I mean.
对。
Right.
比如，她对我非常生气。
Like, she was very angry at me.
我的意思是，她当然生气，因为我做错了事。
I mean, of course she was because I did something wrong.
对。
Right.
所以这是一种提供解释的方式。
So it's a way to offer an explanation.
好的。
All right.
所以这周试着在你的口语中使用它。
So try and use that one in your speech this week.
这是一个非常非常棒的常见英语短语。
It's really, really great common English phrase.
好的。
All right.
So why don't we listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be back to talk a
那我们最后再听一遍对话，之后回来再聊一
little bit more.
点。
Hello.
你好。
Thanks for calling 123 tech help.
感谢致电123技术支持。
I'm Todd.
我是托德。
How can I help you?
有什么可以帮您的？
Hello.
你好。
Can you help me on my computer?
你能帮我看看我的电脑吗？
Oh man.
哦，天哪。
It's okay, sir.
没事的，先生。
Calm down.
冷静点。
What happened?
发生什么事了？
I turned on my laptop and it broke.
我打开笔记本电脑，它就坏了。
I mean, the monitor went black.
我是说，屏幕变黑了。
Okay, sir.
好的，先生。
It sounds like you might have a virus.
听起来你可能中了病毒。
I don't feel sick.
我没觉得不舒服啊。
Let me check.
让我检查一下。
Nope.
没有。
No fever.
没发烧。
I'm fine.
我很好。
No, your computer might have a virus.
不，是你的电脑可能中了病毒。
I mean, it has a bad program on it.
我是说，它里面有个坏程序。
Maybe that's why it crashed.
也许这就是它死机的原因。
I recommend that you run an antivirus program in order to safely remove any unwanted spyware
我建议你运行一个杀毒程序，以便安全地移除任何不需要的间谍软件
or Trojans.
或木马。
Phew.
呼。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
Crash?
死机？
Spyware?
间谍软件？
Trojans?
木马？
What?
什么？
Where?
哪里？
When?
什么时候？
All right.
好的。
So Marco, in today's dialogue, we heard a couple of strange words about computer viruses.
那么马可，在今天的对话中，我们听到了几个关于电脑病毒的奇怪词汇。
One of them you might be familiar with from Greek stories and fables.
其中一个你可能从希腊故事和寓言中熟悉。
A Trojan.
木马。
All right.
好的。
A Trojan.
木马。
So it's a kind of bad software that will hurt your computer.
这是一种会伤害你电脑的恶意软件。
Yeah, it's a type of virus that comes in and it's supposed to be a good program or not
是的，这是一种病毒，它进来时假装是个好程序或者不会
harm your computer, but it's really just a lie.
伤害你的电脑，但实际上只是个谎言。
It's disguised as something else and then it starts to really ruin your computer.
它伪装成别的东西，然后开始真正破坏你的电脑。
They're very, very dangerous.
它们非常非常危险。
Yeah.
是的。
So why do you think it's called a Trojan?
那你觉得为什么它叫木马？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Probably because of a Troy something, because it's very difficult like a Trojan.
可能是因为特洛伊什么的，因为它像木马一样很难对付。
Well, think about the story of the Trojan horse, right?
嗯，想想特洛伊木马的故事，对吧？
You know that story.
你知道那个故事。
So back in ancient Greece, there was a war happening and Troy wanted to defeat its enemy
在古希腊时期，有一场战争，特洛伊想打败它的敌人
and they didn't know how to do it.
但他们不知道怎么做。
So they thought and thought and thought and they came up with an idea.
所以他们想了又想，终于想出了一个主意。
They would build a horse and they would give it as a gift, but inside the horse would be
他们建造了一匹马，把它作为礼物送出，但马里面藏着
warriors, fighters.
战士、斗士。
So when the city opened its doors to this wonderful gift, they would receive a horrible
所以当城市打开大门迎接这个美妙的礼物时，他们收到的却是一个可怕的
gift and attack.
礼物，并遭到攻击。
And so Trojan is like that.
木马就像那样。
It's like software that you think is safe, but then it attacks your computer by surprise.
它就像你以为是安全的软件，但随后它突然攻击你的电脑。
They're very dangerous.
它们非常危险。
And now things have come up like Trojans and worms and a lot of different names for them.
现在出现了像木马、蠕虫等很多不同的名称。
But it's crazy now, although I hear Mac users don't have these problems.
但现在很疯狂，不过我听说Mac用户没有这些问题。
We do not.
我们没有。
If you use a Macintosh computer, you probably have very few problems with viruses and things
如果你使用Macintosh电脑，你很可能很少遇到病毒之类的问题
like that.
。
Wow.
哇。
So we're all in favor for Mac users.
所以我们全都支持Mac用户。
Absolutely.
绝对。
So let us know.
所以告诉我们吧。
Have you had problems with a virus on your computer?
你的电脑遇到过病毒问题吗？
Have you ever called tech support?
你曾经打过技术支持电话吗？
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
希望在那里见到你。
All right.
好的。
Bye, everyone.
大家再见。
Thanks for watching.
感谢观看。